Welcome back, in this second half of the lecture we'll continue with our overview
欢迎回来，在这节课的后半部分，我们将继续概述
of the structure of a compiler. Recall that a compiler has five major phases,
编译器的结构。回想一下编译器有五个主要阶段，
lexical analysis, parsing, semantic analysis, optimization, and code
词法分析、解析、语义分析、优化和编码
generation. And now we're going to briefly talk about each one, and we're going to
一代人。现在我们将简要地讨论每一个问题，我们将
explain how a compiler understands these with an analogy to how humans understand
用人类理解的类比来解释编译器如何理解这些
English. The first step at understanding a program, both for a compiler and for a
英语。理解程序的第一步，对于编译器和
human, is to understand the words. Now, humans can look at this example sentence
人，就是要懂字。现在，人类可以看到这个例句
and immediately recognize that there are four words 'this is a' and 'sentence. And
并立即认识到有四个词‘这是一个’和‘句子。
this is so automatic that you don't even think about it but there is [inaudible]
这是如此自动，以至于你甚至不去想它，但有[听不见]
real computation going on here. You have to recognize the separators, namely the
真正的计算在这里进行。您必须识别分隔符，即
blanks. And the punctuation, things like the periods, and also clues like capital
一片空白。还有标点符号，像句点这样的东西，还有像大写这样的线索
letters. And these help you to divide up this group of letters into, a bunch of
信件。这些帮助你把这组字母分成，一堆
words that you can understand. And just to emphasize that this is not completely
你能听懂的话。我要强调的是，这并不是完全
trivial, let's take a look at this sentence. And you can read this, but it
琐事，我们来看看这句话。你可以读到这个，但是它
takes a little bit of time Because I've put the separators in, in odd places. So
需要一点时间，因为我在奇怪的地方放了分隔符。所以
you can see the word is, the word this, the word a, and the word sentence. But
你可以看到单词is，单词this，单词a和单词句子。但
again this isn't something that comes to you immediately. You actually have to do
再说一次，这不是你马上就会想到的事情。你实际上要做的就是
some work to see where the divisions lie Because they're not given to you in the
有些工作是为了查看划分在哪里，因为它们不是在
way that you're used to. The goal of lexical analysis, then, is to divide the
你习惯的方式。因此，词法分析的目标是将
program text into its words, or what we call in compiler speak, the tokens. So,
将程序文本转化为它的单词，或者我们在编译器中所说的标记。所以,
here's an, an example piece of program text now, instead of a piece of English
这不是一篇英语，而是一段，现在是一段例句的程序课文，而不是一段英语。
text, and let's walk through this and identify the tokens. So, there's some
文本，让我们浏览一下并识别令牌。所以，有一些
obvious ones that are keywords, like if, and then. >> And else that we want to
明显的关键字，比如if，然后。>>否则我们想要
identify. And then there are variable names, things like X, and Y, and Z.
确认身份。然后是变量名，比如X、Y和Z。
There's also constants, things like number one, and the number two. And then there
还有常量，比如数字一和数字二。然后在那里
are some operators, double equals is one, and the assignment operator is another.
是一些运算符，Double Equals是一个运算符，赋值运算符是另一个运算符。
And here's already an interesting question. How do we know that double
这已经是一个有趣的问题了。我们怎么知道这双倍
equals is not two individual equals signs? How do we know that we want this? To be a
等号不是两个人的等号吗？我们怎么知道我们想要这个呢？成为一名
double equal so we want, and not two single equals. Well, we don't know right
所以我们想要双倍相等，而不是两个单一相等。嗯，我们不知道对不对
now but we'll talk about that. >> In the lecture on how we implement Lexico
现在，但我们会讨论这个。>>在我们如何实现Licio的讲座中
analysis. But we're not done with all the tokens in this example either, there's a
分析。但是我们也没有用完本例中的所有令牌，有一个
few more. The semi colons, the punctuation are also tokens, and then the separators
再来几个。分号、标点符号也是标记，然后是分隔符
are also tokens, so here's a blank, that's a token, here's another blank, that's
也是代币，所以这里有一个空格，这是一个代币，这里还有一个空格，那是
another token, and then there are lots of blanks here that serve to separate things
另一个记号，然后这里有很多空格，用来分隔东西
like the keywords and the variable names and other symbols from each other. And
就像关键字、变量名和其他符号彼此不同。和
those are the tokens of this example. So for humans, once the words are understood,
这些是本例中的标记。所以对人类来说，一旦理解了这些话，
the next step is to understand the structure of the sentence, and this is
下一步是理解句子的结构，这是
called parsing. And as we all learned in elementary school, this means diagramming
称为解析。正如我们在小学时学到的，这意味着要画图表
sentences, and these diagrams are trees, and it's a very simple procedure. Let's
句子，这些图表是树，这是一个非常简单的过程。我们走吧
look at this example. This line is a longer sentence. The first step in parsing
看看这个例子。这一行是一个较长的句子。解析的第一步
is to identify the role of each word in the sentence. So we have things like nouns
就是找出每个词在句子中的角色。所以我们有名词之类的东西
and verbs and adjectives. But then, the actual work of parsing is to group these
还有动词和形容词。但是，解析的实际工作是对这些内容进行分组
words together into higher level constructs. So for example, this
将单词组合成更高层次的结构。举个例子，这个
particular sentence consists of a subject, a verb, and an object, okay? And that
特定的句子由主语、动词和宾语组成，好吗？那就是
actually forms an entire sentence. So, right here we have the root of the tree
实际上构成了一个完整的句子。所以，就在这里，我们看到了树根
called a sentence, and that's broken down into constituent parts. The high level
叫做句子，它被分解成几个组成部分。高层
structure, as we said, is subject verb to object. And then the subject is more
结构，正如我们所说的，是主语动词对宾语。然后主题就是更多
complicated, as is the object. And this is an example of parsing an English sentence.
复杂，就像对象一样。这是一个解析英语句子的例子。
The analogy between parsing English text and parsing program text is very strong.
解析英语文本和解析程序文本之间的相似性非常强。
In fact, they're exactly the same thing. So here's our little example piece of code
事实上，它们完全是一回事。下面是我们的一小段示例代码
again, so let's work through parsing it. So, clearly, this is an if then else
再说一次，让我们来解析一下。所以，很明显，这是一种假设，否则
statement, and so, the root of our diagram, of our parse tree, is gonna be if
语句，因此，我们的图和解析树的根将是if
then else. [inaudible] Nothing else consists of three parts. There's a
然后是其他的。[听不见]其他的东西都由三部分组成。有一个
predicate, a then statement, and an L statement. And now let?s look at the
谓词、THEN语句和L语句。现在让我们来看一下
predicate which consists of three pieces. There's a variable, a comparison operator
谓词，由三部分组成。有一个变量，一个比较运算符
and another variable and together those form a relation. So the comparison between
还有另一个变量，这些变量加在一起就形成了一种关系。所以比较一下
two things is one of the things you can have as a valid predicate. Similarly, the
两件事是你可以作为有效谓词的一件事。类似地，
then statement consists of an assignment where Z gets one, and the else statement also
THEN语句由一个赋值组成，其中Z得到一个赋值，而ELSE语句也包含一个赋值
has the form of an assignment, Z gets two. And to, all together this is a parse tree,
有赋值的形式，Z得到两个。加在一起，这是一棵解析树，
of the if-then-else, showing its structure, breaking it up into its
If-Then-Else，显示其结构，将其分解为
constituent pieces. Now, once we've understood the sentence structure, the
成分片。现在，一旦我们理解了句子结构，
next step is to try to understand the meaning, of what has been written. And,
下一步是试着理解所写内容的含义。和,
this is hard. So, actually we don't know how this works for humans still. We don't
这太难了。所以，实际上我们还不知道这对人类是如何起作用的。我们没有
understand, what happens after lexical analysis and parsing. We do know that
理解词法分析和解析之后会发生什么。我们确实知道
people do lexical analysis and parsing in much the same way, that compilers
人们进行词法分析和解析的方式与编译器大致相同
lexically analyze and parse programs. But frankly, understanding meaning is
对程序进行词法分析和解析。但坦率地说，理解意思是
something that is simply too hard for compilers. So, the first important thing
这对编译器来说简直太难了。所以，第一件重要的事
to understand about, semantic analysis is that compilers can only do very limited
要了解，语义分析是编译器只能做非常有限的事情
kinds of semantic analysis. And in particular the kinds of things that
各种语义分析。尤其是那些
compilers generally do are try to catch inconsistencies. So, if the program is
编译器通常会尝试捕捉不一致的地方。所以，如果程序是
somehow self inconsistent, [inaudible] compilers can often notice that and report
不知何故，自不一致的[听不见的]编译器经常会注意到这一点并报告
errors. But they don't really know what the program is supposed to do. As an
错误。但是他们并不真正知道这个项目应该做什么。作为一个
example of the kind of thing that we do in semantic analysis, again, using an analogy
我们在语义分析中所做的这类事情的例子，再一次使用类比
in English, let's consider the following sentence. So, Jack said Jerry left his
在英语中，让我们考虑下面的句子。杰克说杰瑞把他的
assignment at home. And the question is, what, who does his, refer to here? It
家里的作业。问题是，他的在这里指的是谁？它
could be that his refers to Jerry, in which case we would read, Jack said Jerry
可能他指的是杰瑞，在这种情况下，我们会读到，杰克说，杰瑞
left Jerry's assignment at home. Or it could refer to Jack. In which case, we
把杰瑞的任务留在家里了。也可能是指杰克。在这种情况下，我们
could read the sentence as, Jack said Jerry left Jack's assignment at home. And
杰克说杰瑞把杰克的作业忘在家里了。和
without more information, we actually don't know which one. His is referring to,
在没有更多信息的情况下，我们实际上不知道是哪一个。他指的是，
whether it's Jack, or it's Jerry. And even worse, let's take a look at this sentence
不管是杰克，还是杰瑞。更糟糕的是，让我们看看这句话
down here. Jack said, Jack left his assignment at home. And the question is
在这下面。杰克说，杰克把作业忘在家里了。问题是
how many people are actually involved in this sentence? It could be as many as
这句话实际上涉及多少人？可能会有多达
three, there could be two separate Jacks and his, could even refer to somebody
三，可能有两个不同的杰克和他的，甚至可以指某人
completely different. We don't know without seeing the rest of the story. That
完全不同。如果不看这个故事的睡觉，我们就不知道。那
surrounds this sentence, all the possibilities for his. But it could also
围绕着这句话，他的一切可能性。但它也可能
be as few as, only a single person. It could be that Jack and Jack and his are
少到只有一个人。可能是杰克和杰克和他的
all the same person in this sentence. And so this kind of ambiguity is a real
这句话里的所有人都是同一个人。所以这种模棱两可是真正的
problem, in semantic analysis. And the analogy in programming languages is
语义分析中的问题。编程语言中的类比是
variable bindings. So we would have variables, in this case, a variable called
变量绑定。所以我们会有变量，在本例中，变量名为
Jack or maybe more than one variable called Jack. And a programming language is
或者可能不止一个名为jack的变量。一种编程语言是
going to have very strict rules to prevent the kind of ambiguities we had in the
将有非常严格的规则来防止我们在
English sentences on the previous slide. So you know, in this example. Question is
上一张幻灯片上的英语句子。所以你知道，在这个例子里。问题是
what value is printed by this output statement, and the answer is it's going to
此OUTPUT语句打印的值是什么，答案是它将
print four because this use of the variable Jack binds to this definition
打印四，因为变量JACK的使用绑定到此定义
here. And the outer definition is hidden. So the outer definition is not active in
这里。并且外部定义被隐藏。因此，外部定义在中处于非活动状态
this scope because it is hidden by the inner definition and that is just a
这个作用域，因为它被内部定义隐藏，这只是一个
standard rule of a lot of lexically scoped programming languages. Now the pilots
许多词法作用域编程语言的标准规则。现在飞行员们
perform many semantic texts besides analyzing the variable bindings. And so
除了分析变量绑定之外，执行许多语义文本。因此，
here's another example in English. So Jack looked her homework at home. And, under
这里有另一个英语例子。所以杰克在家里看了她的作业。并且，在
the usual naming conventions, assuming that Jack is male, we know there's a type
按照通常的命名惯例，假设杰克是男性，我们知道有一种类型
mismatch between Jack and her. So we know that, whatever her is, it is not Jack.
杰克和她不匹配。所以我们知道，不管她是什么人，都不是杰克。
And, and therefore we known that this sentence is talking about two different
因此我们知道这句话说的是两个不同的
people. And so this is, analogous to type checking. The fourth compiler phase,
人民。这就类似于类型检查。第四编译阶段，
optimization, doesn't have a very strong counterpart in everyday English usage but
优化，在日常英语用法中没有很强的对应性，但是
it's a little bit like editing. And, in fact, it's a lot like what professional
这有点像编辑。事实上，这很像是什么专业人士
editors do when they have to reduce the length of an article to get it down to
当编辑不得不缩短文章的长度以使之降到最低时，他们就会这么做。
some word budget. So, for example, I have this phrase right here, but a little bit
一些文字预算。举个例子，我这里有这样一句话，但有一点
like ending; and if I didn't like it, if I thought it was too long, I could replace
喜欢结尾；如果我不喜欢，如果我觉得太长了，我可以换掉
the middle four words, with two words. Akin to. So now it says, but akin to
中间的四个字，有两个字。类似于。所以现在它说，但类似于
editing, and that means exactly the same thing as the original phrase, but uses
编辑，这与原始短语的意思完全相同，但使用
fewer words. And the goal in program optimization Is to modify the program so
少说几句话。而程序优化的目标是对程序进行修改，从而
that it uses less of some resource. Maybe we want to use less time, we want the
它使用的资源更少。也许我们想用更少的时间，我们想要
program to run faster maybe we want it to use less space so that we can fit more
程序运行得更快，也许我们希望它使用更少的空间，这样我们就可以容纳更多的人
data in memory. For a handheld device we might be interested in reducing the amount
内存中的数据。对于手持设备，我们可能有兴趣降低
of power that it uses. If we have external communication we might be interested in
它所使用的能量。如果我们有外部通信，我们可能会感兴趣
reducing the number of network messages or the number of database accesses. And
减少网络消息数量或数据库访问次数。和
there's any number of resources that we might want to improve other program's use
我们可能想要提高其他程序的使用率
of. So here's a simple example of the kinds of optimizations a program might do.
的。这里有一个简单的例子，说明了程序可能进行的各种优化。
We can have a rule in our compiler that says X equals Y times zero, is the same as
我们的编译器中可以有一条规则，X等于Y乘以零，等于
X equals zero. And this seems like a real improvement, because instead of doing the
X等于零。这似乎是一个真正的进步，因为与其做
multiply, we can just do an assignment. So we save some computation by doing that.
乘法，我们可以只做一个任务。所以我们这样做可以节省一些计算量。
Now unfortunately this is not a correct rule. And this is one of the important
不幸的是，这不是一条正确的规则。这是其中一个重要的
things to know about compiling optimization, is that it's not always
关于编译优化需要知道的事情是，它并不总是
obvious when it's legal to do certain optimizations or not. Now it turns out
很明显，何时进行某些优化是合法的或不合法的。现在事实证明
That this particular rule is valid for integers. Okay, so if X and Y are
此特定规则对整数有效。好的，如果X和Y是
integers, then multiplying by zero is always the same thing as just signing
整数，则乘以零始终等同于仅签名
zero. But, it's invalid for floating point. And why is that, well because you
零。但是，它对浮点数是无效的。为什么呢？因为你
have to know some details of the IEEE floating point standard, but there is a
我必须了解IEEE浮点标准的一些细节，但是有一个
special number in the IEEE standard called not a number and it turns out that
IEEE标准中的特殊数字不是数字，结果是
not a number called a NaN times zero is equal to not a number. Any particular
一个叫做NaN的数字乘以零不等于一个数字。任何特定的
non-number times zero is not equal to zero If X and Y are plotting point numbers, you
如果X和Y正在绘制点编号，则非数字乘以零不等于零
can't do this optimization. In fact, if you did this optimization, it would break
无法进行此优化。事实上，如果您进行此优化，它将中断
certain very important algorithms that rely on the proper propagation of
某些非常重要的算法依赖于
not a number. Finally, the last compiler phase is code generation, often
不是一个数字。最后，最后一个编译器阶段是代码生成，通常是
referred to as Code Gen, and Code Gen, can produce assembly code. That's the most
称为代码生成和代码生成，可以生成汇编代码。那是最多的
common thing that a compiler would produce. But in general, it's a
编译器会生成的常见内容。但总的来说，这是一种
translation into some other language. And this is, entirely analogous to human
翻译成其他语言。这是，完全类似于人类
translation. So just as a human translator might translate, English into French, a
翻译。因此，就像人工翻译可能会将英语翻译成法语一样，一个
compiler will translate a high level program into assembly code. To wrap up,
编译器将高级程序翻译成汇编代码。总而言之，
almost every compiler has the five phases that we outlined. However, the proportions
几乎每个编译器都有我们概述的五个阶段。然而，这一比例
have changed a lot over the years, and if we were to go back to FORTRAN I and
这些年来发生了很大的变化，如果我们回到FORTRANI和FORTRANI
look inside of that compiler, we would probably see a size and complexity that
仔细观察编译器内部，我们可能会看到它的大小和复杂性
looks something like this. We have a fairly complex lexical analysis phase, an
看起来像这样。我们有一个相当复杂的词法分析阶段，
equally complicated parsing phase, a very small semantic analysis phase, a. A fairly
同样复杂的解析阶段，非常小的语义分析阶段，a.相当
involved optimization phase and another fairly involved code generation phase. And
包括优化阶段和另一个相当复杂的代码生成阶段。和
so we see a compiler where the complexity was sp, spread fairly evenly throughout
所以我们看到一个编译器，它的复杂度是sp，相当均匀地分布在各处。
except for its semantic analysis which is very weak in the early days. And today
除了它早期的语义分析非常薄弱之外。而今天
if we look at a modern compiler you'll see almost nothing in lengthening, very little
如果我们看一看现代编译器，你几乎看不到任何加长方面的东西，很少
in parsing, because we have extremely good tools to help us write those two phases.
因为我们有非常好的工具来帮助我们编写这两个阶段。
We would see a fairly involved thematic analysis phase. We would see a very large
我们将看到一个相当复杂的主题分析阶段。我们会看到一个非常大的
optimization phase, and this is in fact the dominant component off all modern
优化阶段，这实际上是所有现代产品的主要组成部分
compilers, and the a small code-generation phase because again we understand that
编译器，以及一个很小的代码生成阶段，因为我们再次理解
phase very, very well. That's it for this lecture. Future lectures, we'll look at
阶段非常非常好。这堂课就讲到这里。在以后的讲座中，我们将关注
each of these phases in detail.
这些阶段中的每一个都有详细的描述。